asiatraveltips.com 2014-02-09

# Privacy Policy - ASIA Travel Tips.com

Thank you for using [ASIA Travel Tips.com](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/). For many years we did not had a Privacy Policy publicly displayed on ASIA Travel Tips.com for the simple reason that most Privacy Policies have a clause that state that it may change at any time. It was for this reason, that we never publicly displayed our policy even though as a company, we have always had a very strict internal Privacy Policy which is followed to the letter. In addition to this, however often do the average user check a site's privacy policy? I know most of us here never do.

Further down you can read the official "more legal" Privacy Policy if you wish, however it really is very simple. Any information that we obtain from you be it, your email, name or other information is never sold or given to any third party (this excludes hotel reservations where your details are shared between us and the hotel where you are making the reservation). We never send out unsolicited email to any of our users at any time. If you feel that you have been receiving something from us which you should not, then please let us know and we will immediately look into the matter. We respect your privacy, in exactly the same way as we respect our own.

Our hotel reservations are made through an encrypted and secure SSL connection meaning that the information your provide when making a reservation is shared only with us and the hotel where you are making the reservation. Also, because many users startedasking for immediate confirmations to their hotel reservations we signed up with a third party that allows us to do just that. This added convenience however does mean that the privacy policy of the third party comes into effect once you pass from our site to theirs.

Now for the more legal version:

Privacy Policy

[ASIA Travel Tips.com](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/) may be referred to below as the site, or the website, or by name.

INFORMATION WE REQUEST

You will not be asked for any personal details that are irrelevant to contacting you. As you are making hotel reservations certain details are required to ensure that the reservation is processed correctly and guaranteed for you as per your reservation.

The type of personal information we request are:    
Name   
Address   
Gender   
Date of birth   
Nationality   
Email address   
Credit Card Information (name of cardholder, credit card number and expiry date)

Travel details, including :

proposed check-in and check-out dates   
number of rooms required   
proposed pick-up and drop-off dates & time   
flight information - flight number, arrival and departure time   
number of passengers, rooms   

We request this information when you make use of our reservation services.

USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We use the information you provide for one or more of the following purposes:

\- To process your travel reservation purchases and confirm your travel arrangements.   
\- To improve our content, service and product offerings.   
\- To provide you with valued and efficient customer support.   
\- To statistically analyze site usage.   
\- To improve our marketing and promotional efforts.

In specific situations, to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our User Agreement. We only share your information with our service providers (hotels) and third party reservation parties as the information is essential to processing your hotel reservations correctly. The sole purpose for this disclosure is to make the ASIA Travel Tips.com web site more effective for you.

DEMOGRAPHIC INFORMATION

Please note that we may provide aggregate demographic statistics (such as browser used, operating system, number of pages viewed etc) about people visiting ASIA Travel Tips.com to third parties but these statistics do not identify any single user by name etc.

HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION

All of your ASIA Travel Tips.com hotel reservation activities are conducted through the most advanced security systems that guarantee communication between your browser and the servers. Information is encrypted to ensure your security and privacy.

ASIA Travel Tips.com uses the industry-standard encryption method Secure Socket Layer (SSL 3.0, RC4 with 128 bit encryption (High); RSA with 1024 bit exchange) protocol to protect your information.

We are constantly looking to upgrade hardware and software to ensure that your experience with ASIA Travel Tips.com is safe, secure and efficient for you, the user.

Other than the purposes and parties aforementioned, your personal information will not be provided knowingly to anyone else which includes advertisers, direct marketing companies, or any other unsolicited mailers or persons.

LATEST TRAVEL NEWS DAILY EMAIL

Subscription is available to our Latest Travel News Daily Email free of charge, simply by providing your email address (no other data is requested) on our travel news page [here](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/LatestTravelNews.htm), or any other page where you see a subscription box on our site.

This information and any other information collected from you is protected under our Privacy Policy as described above and below.

To unsubscribe from our Latest Travel News Daily Email you simply need to reply to the email, changing the subject line to "unsubscribe". The email must be sent from the email address you wish to unsubscribe. No third party un-subscriptions are accepted.

CONTESTS AND PROMOTIONS

We run contests and promotions from time to time on our site in which we ask visitors for contact information (such as their email address). We use this information to contact the winners. In addition, we occasionally participate in or conduct joint contests and promotions with third parties. In these instances, certain information such as name and contact information may be shared with the third parties for contest or promotion eligibility verification purposes or for the selection of winning entries, or to ship prizes and promotional material to those who enter.

Whenever we participate in such a contest or promotion, we explicitly state which third party will receive the information.

Visitors who do share information with these third parties must contact the third party directly to opt out of receiving future mailings from the third party. Should you be chosen as a winner of any of our contests or promotions, you must consent to the disclosure of certain personal information for publicity purposes.

LINKS TO OTHER SITES

ASIA Travel Tips.com may link to other sites operated by third parties. The inclusion of any link to such sites does not imply our endorsement of such hyper-linked sites, but is for your reference and convenience only. We have not reviewed all of the hyper-linked sites and are not responsible for their content or accuracy.

Please note that the privacy policies of these third party sites may differ from ours. We advise you to check the privacy policies of other websites before disclosing any personal information.

ASIA Travel Tips.com also contains advertisements by third parties. Unless otherwise specifically stated on this site, we do not endorse or make any representation regarding the liability, quality or accuracy of any products or services featured in, or linked to any advertisement that appears on this site.

ADVERTISING

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit ASIA Travel Tips.com. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Google, as an example of a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to this site and possible history of other sites on the Internet. This is done in an attempt to make the advertisements of more interest to you and cut down on screen wasteage.

As we do not control the cookies placed on the computer by third party vendors and / or advertising companies it is important to note that it is their privacy policy which controls what information is collected and how.

COOKIES

A cookie is a snippet of text that is sent from a website’s servers and stored on a web browser. Cookies can be used to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times a given ad is shown to you. They can also be used to target more specific and / or relevant information based on browser history.

CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

If we change our privacy policy, we will post our new policy on this page so that you are always informed of the way that we use information we collect. Your continued use of our website following the posting of changes to these terms will mean automatic acceptance of those changes.

In the event that you do not approve of the changes, you may direct requests or comments by [ contacting us](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/Contacts.shtml).

DISCLAIMER

We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our website.

ASIA Travel Tips.com may, at any time and at its sole discretion and without cause or notice, terminate or restrict your access to any component of the site or refuse to give effect to any booking or booking/reservation requested by you, terminate your use of the site, and remove and discard any content within the site, without being required to give any reasons or advance notice to you.

Further, you agree that ASIA Travel Tips.com shall not be liable to you or any third-party for any termination of your access to the site.

ASIA Travel Tips.com reserves the right at any time and from time to time to remove, modify or discontinue, temporarily or permanently any details or aspects of this Privacy Policy or our website.

All rights not expressly granted herein are reserved. This clause shall survive any termination of this agreement.

HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions regarding security and privacy issues, please [ contact us](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/Contacts.shtml).

Last updated : 7 April 2009

**_See other recent news regarding_** : [Airlines](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Airlines), [Aviation](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Aviation), [Flights](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Flights), [Hotels](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Hotels), [Promotions](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Promotion), [New Hotels](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=%22New+Hotel%22), [ Visitor Arrivals](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=%22Visitor+Arrivals%22), [Free Deals](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Free), [Cruises](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Cruises), [ Spas](http://www.asiatraveltips.com/cgi-bin/search/search.pl?Terms=Spa)
